## Hubungi

amidrakhman@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/amidrakhman (LinkedIn)

#### Keahlian Teratas

Batch Processing Aqua Data Studio MySQL

#### Certifications

Data Wrangling Python

Data Quality with Python for Beginner

Database Design and Programming with SQL

Menggunakan ORDER BY untuk Mengurutkan Data

Fundamental SQL Group By and Having

# **Amid Rakhman**

Data Engineer | Data Enthusiast

Jawa Barat, Indonesia

## Ringkasan

I am a Data Engineer with experience build Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) Data Pipeline using tools such as SQL Server Integration Service and Pentaho Data Integration. Experience databases such as SQL Server, PostgreSQL and MySQL. I understand SQL and Python Programming Languages for Professional Data.

## Pengalaman

PT Graha Karya Informasi Data Engineer Desember 2023 - Present (8 bulan) Jakarta, Indonesia

Placement to Client: PT Asuransi Kredit Indonesia (Askrindo)

- Develop ETL Pipeline to process reconciliation data between Askrindo Core System and Finance & Accounting Management System
- 2. Maintenance of the ETL pipeline to improve existing process
- 3. Data validation and look for root cause at reconciliation process to ensure appropriate data quality
- 4. Preparing data through tickets in the desk service system for the needs of the business users
- 5. Provide data for audit to support business process

#### Akuntplus

Junior Data Engineer

November 2022 - Desember 2023 (1 tahun 2 bulan)

Jakarta, Jakarta Raya, Indonesia

- 1. Build systems to collect, process, and validate data
- 2. Responsible for ETL (Extract Transform Load) process in a system
- 3. Collaborate with other developers, including Web Developer and VB.NET Developer
- 4. Create System Integration Testing (SIT) document and User Acceptance Testing (UAT)
- 5. Responsible for ETL related bugs found during SIT and UAT

Page 1 of 3

Kalbe Nutritionals (PT Sanghiang Perkasa)

Project-Based Virtual Intern : Data Engineer Kalbe Nutritionals x Rakamin Academy

Oktober 2023 - Oktober 2023 (1 bulan)

Area DKI Jakarta

In this Program, I learned:

Data Warehouse Fundamental

Understanding the concept of Fact Table, Dimension Table and Schema Design

Understanding the concept and implementation of OLAP, Big Data and Data Warehouse in Cloud Computing

Python for Data Engineering

SQL for Data Engineering

ETL Process using Pentaho and Airflow

### BTPN Syariah

Project-Based Virtual Intern : Data Engineer BTPN Syariah x Rakamin Academy

Mei 2023 - Juni 2023 (2 bulan)

Indonesia

Introduction to TSQL, TSQL Data Types, TSQL Statements, TSQL Clause, TSQL Transaction Control, TSQL Function, TSQL Filter Aggregate and Duplicate, TSQL Date String and Numeric, Operate TSQL on a real world tasks, Introduction to Data Modeling, Data Modeling Best Practices, ERD Diagram, Data Modeling Case Study, Data Visualization, Installing Tableu, Tableu Component and Features, Data Visualizing with Tableu, SQL Server, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL Server Integration Service Concept

Central AI (PT Central Artificial Intelligence) Internship Data Scientist Maret 2022 - Juli 2022 (5 bulan) Indonesia

Implementation Named Entity Recognition Indonesian Language in Chatbot

PT. Roda Prima Lancar Production Operator Juli 2020 - Juni 2022 (2 tahun) Karawang, Jawa Barat, Indonesia

PT Yamaha Indonesia Motor Mfg Production Operator

## Februari 2018 - Februari 2020 (2 tahun 1 bulan)

Karawang, Jawa Barat, Indonesia

PT Toyota Motor Manufacturing Indonesia Production Operator November 2015 - November 2017 (2 tahun 1 bulan)

Karawang, Jawa Barat, Indonesia

## Pendidikan

Universitas Buana Perjuangan Karawang S1, Informatics Engineering · (September 2018 - Agustus 2022)